Roberth Rivero

Petroleum Engineer/Production Technologist

Email: roberthrivero@yahoo.com

Technical Profile

An experienced (20 years) all-rounder with knowledge of Production Engineering, Reservoir Engineering, Well Completion and Well Integrity in onshore and offshore environments with E&P and consultant companies; experience in reservoir management, and field development strategies for New Fields and in Brown Field development projects.

Greatly, motivational team leader and team member with experience of developing teams and maximising performance in an optimal partnership environment. Analytical-technical professional who enjoy working with stakeholders and colleagues. Able to adapt to new situations in different departments and with diverse cultures, English & Spanish speaker.

I do enjoy share my years of experience with those younger and less experienced by couching and technical sessions of my core competences:

Work Experience

- Production Engineering, various Artificial lift systems
- Well completion design
- Well Integrity and Standards
- Workover and well interventions
- Production enhancement (fracture and acid treatments)
- Well/Field performance and optimization
- Reservoir Engineering
- Unconventional reservoirs
- Cutting Re-Injection Projects
- EOR Projects
- · Project Management,
- Screening Investment Opportunities

Senior Petroleum Engineer, Halliburton Algeria

Period: August 2017 – present, Location: Hassi Messaoud, Algeria

Role: part of a group of PEs who technically support all Sonatrach & IOCs on production optimization, well completions, interventions, design and optimization of gas lift and ESPs wells, hydraulic fracturing, artificial lift design-optimization and screening, water and gas shut-off and implementation of new technologies

Senior Petroleum Engineer / Production Technologist, Maersk Oil, DK

Period: August 2014 – 2016, **Location:** Maersk Oil, DK; Offshore Assets in the Danish Sector **Role:** tasked to provide peer assist in Well Integrity and production optimization to the Danish assets. Activities:

- Provide PE/PT advice and peer review for redevelopment opportunities on offshore assets
- QAQC acid and hydraulic fracturing treatments for carbonate wells.
- Act as technical focal point well integrity on offshore assets, member of the Well Integrity Board, drafted WIM documents and calculation model for MAASP and rolled-out across all assets
- QAQC and performed Tubing Stress Analysis (TSA) for new completions, WO & wells with critical
 well integrity issues.
- Couching PEs and PTs less experience personnel on generalities of PE, production enhancement and well integrity.

Senior Petroleum Engineer / Production Technologist, Shell

Period: June - 2012 – August 2014, **Location:** Europe, Middle East and Africa, Offshore/onshore fields **Role:** supported multiple projects which went from screening new investment opportunities to field developments, day-to-day support to operating assets, offshore & onshore. Additional activities:

- Development Plan for Tight Gas & Unconventional plays prospects (Russia, Egypt, Tunisia, and Ukraine) which involved, hydraulic fracturing design, dewatering existing wells and water management
- Act as technical focal point for stimulations within the North Sea area, hydraulic fracturing design.
- Sand prediction assessment for new developments in Kazakhstan and Gabon

Roberth Rivero

Petroleum Engineer/Production Technologist

Email: roberthrivero@yahoo.com

- PE support for produced water reinjection and CRI projects in Gabon and Kazakhstan.
- Technical support for redevelopment and field re-instatement for Fram, Gannet, Penguins and L13FF fields in the North Sea.
- PE for a FDP in Deep Water Field Nigeria.

Principal Petroleum Engineer / Production Technologist, Senergy, UK

Period: May 2007 – June 2014, **Location:** based in United Kingdom and supported Europe, Africa, Americas, Asia and Middle East

Role: technical support to multiple FDP, screening new investments, likewise support to small-medium operators on their operations.

- Production enhancement design and execution, multi-stage fracturing on horizontal-openhole wells, etc.
- Optimize production/injection well management, production surveillance, water management; manage scale, erosion and other assurance issues, and conformance control.
- PE support for FDPs for multiple reservoir types i.e. carbonates, sandstones, unconventional reservoirs in Europe, North Africa and Russia.
- Artificial lift selection, design and optimization, onshore/offshore fields
- Well performance for CCS, CO₂-EOR projects and Water flooding. Execute completion basis of design for CO₂ injectors and CO₂-rich fluid producers.
- Well Integrity review for well producer and injectors
- Troubleshooting of gas wells with liquid loading; deliquification of gas wells
- Completion basis of design, metallurgy selection TSAs for new and existing completions.
- Well Intervention planning and requirements light, medium and heavy interventions, equipment procurement
- Long term (day-to-day) petroleum engineering support for artificial lift (gas lift, SRPs, ESPs) design and optimization

Senior Petroleum Engineer, Open SA, Venezuela

Period: June 2004 – February 2007, Location: Eastern Venezuela

Role: Providea link between the petroleum engineering and field development team, well engineering, production, and facilities with notable achievements.

- Well intervention programming and operational support, on-site supervision and support at the rig site, QHSE input, post job performance review, troubleshooting and execution.
- Construction of "Integrated Asset Modelling" for assessing the production gathering network,
- Management of Production Sharing Contracts (PSC's), preparation of AFE level and budgetary time and cost estimates.
- Management well with production chemistry issues (i.e. asphaltenes, scaling) and corrosion issues on well exposed to high CO₂ and H₂S
- Annual well reviews, well-field production surveillance for maintain daily production
- Design and execution of acid-matrix stimulations and proppant-laden fracture / acid frac stimulation
- Water flooding monitoring and optimization of water injectors, assessment of thermal fracturing.
- Upper and lower completion (gravel packs) design including Artificial Lift (gas lift and ESPs)

Production Technologist / Petroleum Engineer, Gesca, Venezuela

Period: January 2003 – May 2004, Location: Lagunillas, Venezuela

Role: my role within included being responsible for well opportunity management,

- Reservoir data gathering, plan and data validation, PE support to field development plans and redevelopment of Brown Field studies
- PE support to Steam assisted producers, steam injector wells, cyclic steam injection on producers; well completion design.
- Lower and upper completion design, material selection, Completion design for well on ESP, SRP, PCP and Gas Lift systems. Sand control design and execution (OHGP in horizontal and vertical wells)

Roberth Rivero

Petroleum Engineer/Production Technologist

Email: roberthrivero@yahoo.com

Reservoir Engineer, PDVSA, Venezuela

Period: June 1998 – January 2003, Company, Location: Barinas, Venezuela

Role: Reservoir, petroleum, and production for various oil and gas assets which involved technical support to activities as:

- Provided reservoir engineering expertise, including reservoir characterization, material balance technique and DCA analysis to the field development. Identify and evaluate new development opportunities through vertical, horizontal new wells and workovers.
- Well testing planning, execution and interpretation.
- Reserves Annual Booking, Asset Annual Business Planning, Budgeting.
- Water and sand production management (water shut-off strategies and sand excluding measures).
- Feasibility and implementation of new technologies i.e. Inverted Coning, Down Hole Hydrocyclones, Chemical Water Shut-Off and Sand Control Techniques.

Qualification

- Specialization in Well-Reservoir Productivity CIED-PDVSA, Venezuela 2001
- Bsc. Petroleum Engineering, University of Zulia, Venezuela 1993 1998